

My Contact

kazi.sifat2013@gmail.com

(L) +01537244273

 22/21, block-2, Khilji Rd, Mohammadpur Dhaka-1207.

in/kazisifatalmaksud/

/KaziSifatAlMaksud

Portfolio

Skill

- Programming PHP, Java, Python, C, C++.
- Mobile Pro. Android Stdio, XML, Java.
- Database MySQL, Oracle Apex, MongoBD, SOLlite.
- Web Design Ajax, PHP, JavaScript, Jquery, RestAPI, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Puppeteer, Preline UI.
- Web Framework Laravel, Flask, Nextjs.
- **Tools** Docker, cPanel, hPanel, Git, Figma, AutoCAD, XAMPP, Ulpath, drawio.

Project (Professional at SPL)

In Hose ERP

Key Responsibilities:

- Developed and maintained multiple modules, including the Supply Chain Module, Task Management Module, HRM Module, Finance and Accounts, and Inventory Management Module.
- Purchase and Store: Managed the entire process from requisition to accounts approval, including credit, cash, sub-contract purchases, bill entry, audits, and accounts approval.
- HRM: Employee monthly salary, fuel, extra allowances, arrears, meal bill, KPI generator, employee leave, attendance report management etc.
- Daily Activity: Managed tasks, meetings, top management issues, and implemented an automated evaluation process etc.
- Maintain High Performance and Security Standard.
- Developed and designed a clickable *Real Estate Email Template* for Marketing Team.

Kazi Sifat Al Maksud

Laravel | PHP | Full Stack Web Developer.

Career Objective

Building up a career in a challenging and dignified position by acquiring a job in the development field in software industry where I can develop career with experienced software engineers and grow my abilities to a greater level and where creativity, honesty, sincerity, skill, and performance are the criteria for one's appraisal.

Education Background

Jahangirnagar University Dhaka, Bangladesh.

January 2024 - Present

MSc. In Computer Science and Engineering CGPA: **3.90** out of **4** (*Credits Earned:* 9/33).

East West University, Dhaka, Bangladesh

September 2019 - September 2023

BSc. In Computer Science and Engineering.

CGPA: 3.38 out of 4.

Major in **Software Engineering.**

Professional Experience

Executive, Technology -Software | Suvastu Properties Ltd.

2nd, December 2023 - Present

Key Responsibilities:

- Maintain, redesign, implement, update, and test the inhouse ERP system using PHP, Ajax, JS, and Laravel Framework.
- Maintain the official website using Laravel Framework.
- Design and manage the Relational Database Management System.
- Provide technical support if employees encounter any issues.

IT- Intern | Iconic Engineering Limited

July 2023 - September 2023

Key Responsibilities:

- Developed and maintaining <u>lconic</u> website. Technologies: Nextjs, laravel, git version control etc
- Give Presentation on zoho one (ERP System)

Freelancer | Fiverr Market Place

October 2023 - March 2024

Activement:

- level 1 Seller with 5 out of 5 Ratings.
- Successfully Complete 11 orders, working with 5 international clients.
- 2 Mini ERP system with Laravel.

Publications

Blockchain in Concurrent Green lot-based **Agriculture:**

Discussion, Analysis, and Implementation ICO-2023:

6th International Conference on Intelligent Computing & Optimization 2023, Hua Hin,

Award

The Medha Lalon Scholarship

(Fall 2022 - Summer 2023) Back to Back 2 years. Issued by East West University

Best Project Award

18 September 2022 Issued by East West University

A+ Category Award

Digital Innovation Fair-2017

Issued by Digital Innovation .

3rd Prize Nazrul Conference Award

• for Recitation Competition- 2018

Extracurricular

EWU Programming Club Jan 2021 - Jan2024

General Member

Science Club, Bhasha Soinik Ajit Guha College August 2016 - April 2018

• 2nd Lead Position



Cultural & Event Management Club, Bhasha Soinik Ajit Guha College

August 2016 - April 2018

• 1st Lead Position and 1st Lead Anchor

PLHSC Sports Clab August 2013 - April 2015

• Captain (All-Rounder)



References

Md. Shah Alam Khan

Deputy Manager (Technology - Software)

Suvastu Properties Ltd,

Suvastu Imam Square, 5th Floor 65-Gulshan Avenue, Gulshan-1, Dhaka 1212, Bangladesh.

Mobile: +8801313498881

E-mail: technology@suvastu.com

Dr. Ahmed Wasif Reza

Professor, Department of CSE

East West University, Dhaka.

A/2, Jahurul Islam Avenue, Jahurul Islam City, Aftabnagar, Dhaka-1212, Bangladesh. Phone

(Off.):+880209666775577 Mobile: +8801780099173 E-mail: wasif@ewubd.edu

Recent Project

Orderr360 - Mini ERP System

- Laravel, Stripe, Firebase.

- This ERP Application is designed for paint shop owners and contractors. It centralizes all aspects of the business, Allowing the head owner to assign painters to jobs, manage orders, inventory, and job details, catering to painters, shop owners, contractors, and customers alike.

lacksquare

Eternalmessages - Chat Application.

• Laravel, Preline UI, Ajax, Figma.

- You can chat with your loved ones by pre-uploading videos, images, and text messages.

- After that, there will be a chat room available for chatting with your loved ones.

Projects (UNDERGEADUARE)

EesyGo - Indoor Navigation with Easy Data Collection Mobile App

B.Sc. Capstone Project

-App that collects dataset using mobile sensors.

-Easy data collection mobile app for indoor navigation, converting user input into maps to find shortest path destinations. Technology: Android Studio, API, PHP

Café Shop Management System Website

- PHP, HTML, CSS, JS, MySQL and XAMPP

IntelliCash - Smart ATM Simulator System.

- Using Laravel Framework, HTML, CSS, JS, Boostrap

Gadget Shop Mobile App

-Android Studio, Java, PHP Own Process API, Firebase and **SQLite**

Gadget Shop Management System Website

- Flask, HTML, CSS, JS and MongoDB.

FIFA World Cup 2022 Database Project

- Implemented using SQL, Oracle Apex and HTML, CSS, and JS.

Event Management Mobile App

- Android Studio, Java, PHP Own Process API, and SQLite.

Sentiment Analysis from Bangla Sentence using Neural **Network Algorithms**

Natural Language Data preprocessing and Classification

ATM Simulation Management System

- ATM Simulation Management System using Java, Swing and File (for Storage)

https://github.com/KaziSifatAlMaksud

https://kazisifatalmaksud.github.io/KaziSifatAlMaksud1/

https://www.dropbox.com/home/Extracurricular/Cultural

